Andrew vonderLuft

DEVOPS / SYSADMIN / DEVELOPER / MANAGER

avonderluft@avlux.net 360.600.9962 Brush Prairie, WA United States

Profile

Creative thinker with broad experience in developing and implementing I.T. solutions

Skills

DevOps/SysAdmin

Automation of everything for software deployment

Software Developer

Effective applications that delight users and maintainers

I.T. Manager

Strategic decision-making and collaborative oversight

Technical

Deploy Automation	Ruby, Rails	AWS console & API	DNS, Apache, Nginx	SQL, PostgreSQL
CI/CD engineering	RSpec, Minitest	EC2, ELB, ALB, SGs	vim, bash, cron	MySQL, SQLite
Configuration Mgmt	Capistrano	RDS, S3, Glacier	Monit, JMeter	XML, HTML, HAML
Github integration	Puppet, TeamCity	Cloudfront	PHP, WP, WebSVN	Javacript, JQuery
CDN configuration	JIRA, Redmine	VPC, Route53	Java, Tomcat	Node, React, et al.
Git, Subversion	Travis, Jenkins	CloudWatch	IIS, ActiveDirectory	CSS, SASS

Experiences

Renew Financial - https://renewfinancial.com DevOps Engineer III

Jan 2015 - Nov 2017

- Devops Engineer in
- Automate, integrate and manage software deployment lifecycle
- Configure and manage continuous integration tools and build systems
- Provide system resources to Software Development and QA teams
- Maintain internal systems to maximize automation and repeatability
- Monitor and optimize systems and application performance
- Ensure secure operation and configuration of all technical infrastructure

Con-way - https://www.xpo.com

Apr 2002 - Jan 2015

Senior Software Engineer

- Design, configure and deploy new corportate web infrastructure
- Configure web application components including Apache, Nginx, Passenger, Bundler, MySQL, DNS
- Develop and extend internal and external websites using Ruby, Rails, Redmine and RadiantCMS
- Configure and manage Source Control Management using Subversion and Git
- Mentor I.T. staff in use of development tools and technologies
- Implement XML web services for Rate Requests, Bills of Lading, et al.

Manager of Information Architecture

- Oversee staff of over 20 to manage network infrastructure for over 400 locations
- Prepare and present detailed proposal, including ROI, for change to thin client architecture
- Research, select and deploy thin client network solution for all company locations
- Facilitate communication and collaboration between technical staff and executives

Con-way - https://www.xpo.com

Feb 1996 - Dec 1999

Senior Systems Analyst

- Research, implement and maintain logistics operations software for new business line
- Prepare and present design and implementation plans to VP levels
- Provision and configure operations servers and network
- Write and execute complete data conversion to new operations software
- Administer Windows NT and Unix servers
- Teach front-end staff software usage for operations

AVLUX Enterprises, LLC - https://avlux.net/

Jul 2000 - present

Principal

- Oversee operations for homegrown hosting company
- Systems and software setup and configuration
- Administer servers, monitoring and backup

Pacific Data Group - http://www.comsys.us/

Mar 1995 - Feb 1996

Systems Analyst (Contractor)

- Lead Analyst for Order Entry Systems code, test and quality assurance
- Job flow dependency analysis and tuning
- On-call support

Projects

RadiantCMS - http://radiantcms.org/

2008

Core committer. Radiant is a Rails-based, no-fluff, open source content management system

Education

Reed College - http://reed.edu/, Portland, OR U.S.A

1977 - 1981

B.A.

Languages Ruby SQL Bash

Acquainted Acquainted Acquainted

Links github -

https://github.com/avonderluft

rubygems -

http://rubygems.org/profiles/avonderluft

<u>linkedin -</u>

 $\underline{\text{http://www.linkedin.com/in/avonderluft}}$

 $And rew \ von der Luft - \underline{avonder luft@avlux.net} - 360.600.9962$